Imagine you're driving in a city with your friend.
友人と一緒に街を運転していると想像してみてください
You have a goal that you're trying to get to.
到達しようとしている目標があります
You are sitting in the passenger seat and your friend is driving.
あなたは助手席に座っていて 友人は運転しています
You plug that goal into Google Maps and you
目標をグーグル マップに組み込めば
get some route that will get you to your destination.
目的地に行くルートを取得します
The driver shouldn't be concerned about the details of what the route exactly is.
運転手はルートが正確かどうか 詳細について心配するべきではありません
Right, because the driver trusts that you acting, as the navigator,
運転手はあなたが注意を払っていると信じているため ナビゲーターとして
will tell them what maneuvers they need to make and it's
何をする必要があるかを伝えます
understood that they are just responsible for executing them.
また ナビゲーションを行う必要があります
In this situation, the responsibilities of the passenger are
この状況では
analogous to the responsibilities of a behavior planner in a self-driving car.
乗客の責任は自動運転車の行動計画担当者の責任と似ています
So if you tell your friend to go left, they will do that.
友人に左へ行くように言えば 友人はそうするでしょう
And when you tell the driver to pass a slow vehicle,
運転手に遅い車を抜かすように言えば
the driver won't worry about whether they have enough time to do so because they
運転手は 車を抜かすのに十分な時間があるかどうかを心配する必要はありません
will assume that you have thought about that
あなたが前の車を抜かせるのに
and that you're confident that they can make it.
自信があると 信じているからです
But the navigator is not responsible for safety.
しかしナビゲーターは安全に対して責任を負いません
If you tell the driver to get back to the left lane but there is a vehicle in the way,
運転者に左車線に戻るように言うけれども邪魔な車があるならば
you will assume that they will wait to move
安全に移動するのに十分なスペースができるまで
left until there is enough room to do so safely.
左に移動するのを待つと仮定します
The navigator will also tell the driver when to keep their lane and when it is
ナビゲーターは 車線を維持するのか 車線を変更するのか 速度調整をする
time to turn or change lanes or maybe adjust the speed.
タイミングを運転手に教えます
And finally, once you're arrived at your destination,
最後に 目的地に到着した時点で
you will tell the driver to stop.
運転手に停止するように言います
So, to summarize, the behavior planner is
要約すると 行動プランナーは現在
currently a black box which takes as input a map of the world,
入力として世界地図
a route to the destinations,
目的地への道のり
and predictions about what other static and dynamic obstacles are likely to do,
他の静的および動的な障害が起こりそうなことについての予測をとり
and it produces as output a adjusted maneuver for the vehicle which
出力として車両のための調整された操縦をするブラックボックスです
the trajectory planner is responsible for reaching collision-free, smooth, and safe.
トラジェクトリー計画者は 衝突なく 滑らかな運転で 安全に到着することに対して責任があります
The goal of this lesson is to open up
このレッスンの目的は このブラックボックスを開き
this black box and learn how to implement a behavior planner.
行動プランナーを実装する方法を学ぶことです
So the responsibilities of
そのため
the behavior module are to suggest maneuvers which are feasible,
行動モジュールの責任は 可能な限り安全で 合法で
as safe as possible, legal, and efficient.
効率的な操作を提案することです
What the behavior planner is not responsible
行動プランナーが担当していないのは
for are execution details and collision avoidance.
実行の詳細と衝突回避です
The approach to behavior planning we are going to teach in
このレッスンで教える行動計画へのアプローチは
this lesson is the same one used by most of the vehicles,
DARPA アーバン チャレンジで優勝したものも含めて
including the winning one in the DARPA Urban Challenge.
ほとんどの車両で使用されているものと同じです
In fact, it's the approach to
実際 メルセデスが
behavior planning that Mercedes used in their Bertha Benz Drive,
ベルタ ベンツ ドライブで使用していたアプローチは
which you can see is capable of handling
交差点のナビゲーションや
complex traffic situations like navigating intersections and dense urban traffic.
密集した都市交通などの複雑な交通状況を処理することができることです
And while this approach is not necessarily the most common anymore,
このアプローチは必ずしも最も一般的なものではなくなりましたが
for reasons we will discuss later,
後で議論する理由により
it is widely known in the field and it does give
この分野で広く知られており 行動プランナーで起こっていること
a very high-level understanding of what is going on in a behavior planner.
について高度な理解を提供します